A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 1-3254 FA739A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Technical assistance in the in-service training of Pakistani Civil Servants since 1958 (Reports 000759), 1966; Niehoff, Richard O. (Box 38)
  A paper published by the Asia Studies Center, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan. Title sufficient as abstract.
  Civil service -- Bangladesh; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Bangladesh; Research institutes -- Bangladesh; Rural development -- Bangladesh; Local government -- Bangladesh; Pakistan Academy for Rural Development, Comilla
- Local government in East Pakistan: a study of district councils and municipal committees made at the request of the Secretary of Basic Democracies and Local Government (Reports 000760), 1964; Niehoff, Richard O.; Platt, George M. (George Milo) (Box 38)
  Alternatives are examined for improving administration, staffing, and financing of the local government in East Pakistan.
  Local government -- Bangladesh; Public administration -- Bangladesh; Bangladesh. District Councils
- Review of Oakland Economic Development Council, Oakland, California, May 25-26 (Reports 000761), 1966; Chandler, Edgar H. S. (Edgar H. Storer), 1904- (Box 38)
  The accomplishments and future strategy of the Oakland Economic Development Council are evaluated. Review members include: S. M. Miller, Clifford J. Campbell, William Pincus,James V. Cunningham, Paul N. Ylvisaker, Mildred Epstein, Mildred and Charles St
  Community organization; Political participation; Power (Social sciences); Oakland Economic Development Council (Oakland)
- Report to the members of the Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law (Reports 000762), 1964; Tweed, Harrison, 1885-1969; Segal, Bernard G. (Bernard Gerard), 1907-1997 (Box 38)
  The efforts of the committee to encourage and coordinate the participation of United States lawyers in racial problems are discussed.
  06700020
  Civil rights -- United States; Lawyers -- United States; Race discrimination -- United States; Washington Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law
- Greek-Turkish Economic Cooperation Project: transportation survey: Greece and Turkey (Reports 000763), 1966; Smith, S. P. (Box 38)
  A cooperative project between Greece and Turkey to develop road transport of fresh fruit and vegetables to the Western European market area is discussed.
  Farm produce -- Greece; Farm produce -- Turkey; Transportation -- Greece; Transportation -- Turkey
- Greece and Turkey: mutual economic interests (Reports 000764), 1964; Psomiades, Harry J. (Box 38)
  Tourism, fishing industry, agricultural marketing, and the distribution of electricity are among the possible projects for Greece and Turkey's mutual economic development.
  Tourism -- Greece; Tourism -- Turkey; Fisheries -- Greece; Fisheries -- Turkey; Farm produce -- Greece; Farm produce -- Turkey
- A university librarian looks ahead (Reports 000765), 1963; Bryant, Douglas W. (Douglas Wallace), 1913- (Box 38)
  A Harvard librarian describes for a Japanese audience the future of the American library with regard to facilities and services.
  Libraries -- United States; Academic libraries -- United States
- Bibliography on science and world affairs (Reports 000766), 1964; Rettig, Richard A. (Box 39)
  The bibliography is a survey of literature relevant to the general area of science and foreign policy.
  06300474
  191 p.
  Arms control -- Bibliography; International relations -- Bibliography; Nuclear warfare -- Bibliography; Outer space--Exploration -- Bibliography; United Nations. U.S. Department of State. Foreign Service Institute
- Trends and choices in graduate education (Reports 000767), 1959; Berelson, Bernard, 1912-1979 (Box 39, Reel R-9301)
  Universities and colleges -- Graduate work -- United States; Doctoral programs -- United States
- The nature of the university: some tentative notes for discussion (Reports 000769), 1960; Keyes, H. M. R. (Box 39)
  The philosophy, nature, scope, and history of the university are outlined.
  Universities and colleges; Education -- History; Education, Higher; Education -- Philosophy
- Cooperation among American colleges and universities (Reports 000770), 1960; Cowley, W. H. (William Harold), 1899-1978 (Box 39)
  05990395
  University cooperation -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States
- Inter-university cooperation. Part I, General statement (Reports 000771), 1961; Porter, Willis P., 1908-1985 (Box 39)
  The role and influence of American higher education in world affairs is described.
  University cooperation -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; International relations; International education -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States
- The services performed by American colleges and universities for agriculture and industry (Reports 000772), 1960; Cowley, W. H. (William Harold), 1899-1978 (Box 39)
  An overall review is given of the integration of America colleges and universities into the life of the nation and the history and present status of the services performed by these institutions for agriculture and industry.
  Universities and colleges -- United States; Agriculture -- United States; Industries -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States
- A comparison of Latin American and North American higher education (Reports 000773), 1960; Havighurst, Robert J. (Robert James) (Box 39, Reel R-9301)
  The structure, relation to state, functions, and operations of North American and Latin American universities are compared.
  Education, Higher -- Latin America; Education, Higher -- United States; Education--Latin America -- History; Education -- United States -- History; Universities and colleges -- Latin America; Universities and colleges -- United States; Comparative education
- American cooperation with Brazilian universities (Reports 000774), 1960; Havighurst, Robert J. (Robert James) (Box 39)
  University cooperation -- United States; University cooperation -- Brazil; Universities and colleges -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Brazil; Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Higher -- Brazil
- Cooperation between British and American universities: Especially in underdeveloped areas (Reports 000775), 1960; Lewis, L. J. (Leonard John); Bigelow, Karl W. (Karl Worth) (Box 39)
  Attention is focused on British-American contacts in underdeveloped countries in which universities and university representatives of both metropolitan nations have an interest.
  University cooperation -- United States; University cooperation -- England; Universities and colleges -- England; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- England; Education, Higher -- United States; International relations
- Soviet education in world affairs (Reports 000776), 1960; Medlin, William K. (Box 39)
  Comparisons between American and Soviet higher education are made and areas of mutual interests, though few, are explored.
  International relations; Universities and colleges -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Soviet Union Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Higher -- Soviet Union; University cooperation -- United States; University cooperation -- Soviet Union
- American cooperation with Japanese universities (Reports 000777), 1960; Ike, Nobutaka (Box 39)
  Education, Higher -- Japan; Education, Higher -- United States; University cooperation -- Japan; University cooperation -- United States; International relations; Universities and colleges -- Japan; Universities and colleges -- United States; International education
- Higher education in mainland China and its implications for world affairs (Reports 000778), 1960; Hu, Changdu, 1920- (Box 39)
  International relations; Education, Higher -- China; Universities and colleges -- China
- The advancement of education in Nigeria and the United States through the activities and cooperative effort of institutions of higher education (Reports 000779), 1960; Hannah, Harold W. (Box 39)
  University cooperation -- United States; University cooperation -- Nigeria; Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Higher -- Nigeria; Universities and colleges -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Nigeria
- Role of university education in Arab life with special reference to the possible cooperation of American universities (Reports 000780), 1960; Akrawi, Matta, 1901-1982 (Box 39)
  University cooperation -- Arab countries; University cooperation -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Arab countries; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- Arab countries; Education, Higher -- United States
- Cooperation in higher education: India and the United States (Reports 000781), 1960; Olson, R. O. (Box 39)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Higher -- India; Universities and colleges -- United States; Universities and colleges -- India; University cooperation -- United States; University cooperation -- India
- Education development in Thailand and the role of inter-university cooperation (Reports 000782), 1960; Porter, Willis P., 1908-1985 (Box 39)
  University cooperation -- Thailand; University cooperation -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Thailand; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- Thailand; Education, Higher -- United States
- Long-range institutional programs abroad (Reports 000783), 1960; Porter, Willis P., 1908-1985 (Box 39)
  The future role of the American university in foreign countries is assessed.
  University cooperation -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States; International relations
- Inner content versus academic content in public schools (Reports 000784), 1967; Fantini, Mario D.; Weinstein, Gerald (Box 39)
  Paper presented at the 44th annual meeting of the American Orthopsychiatric Association, Washington, D.C., March 20-23, 1967. Curriculum change and development that would be relevant to the student and thus lead to an affective behavioral change is propos
  Public schools -- United States; Educational accountability -- United States; Behavior modification -- United States; Poor children -- United States; Curriculum planning -- United States
- Comparative education programs: Problems and prospects (Reports 000785), 1960; Gross, Neal Crasilneck, 1920- (Box 40, Reel R-9301)
  The report is a study towards the development and strengthening of research and training programs in comparative education at American universities.
  Comparative education; Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States
- Availability of information for water resources decision-making (Reports 000786), 1966; Fox, Irving K. (Box 40)
  Problems in developing an independent institutional structure to deal with water use decisions are presented.
  Research and Education
  Water-supply -- United States
- The establishment of an applied economic research and feasibility study unit within the proposed Turkish Business and Industry Development Foundation (Reports 000787), 1965; Appleton, Henri; Baynes, Peter A.; Hannington, Gilbert; Verhulst, Michel (Box 40)
  06500295
  Turkish Management Association
  Economics -- Research -- Turkey; Industrialization -- Turkey; Turkish Management Association
- Citrus observations in Egypt, United Arab Republic (Reports 000788), 1965; Chapman, Homer Dwight, 1898-2005 (Box 40)
  The important citrus areas in Egypt are surveyed to investigate climate, soil, tree-growing conditions, and management practices, as related to orchard performance.
  06000194
  Citrus -- Egypt; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Egypt
- Report on the administration of the University of Jordan (Reports 000789), 1965; Davis, Harvey H. (Box 40, Reel R-9301)
  Following an appraisal of the administration of the University of Jordan, the regulations concerning the Board of Trustees, teaching staff, nonacademic personnel, scholarships, purchasing, and travel are surveyed.
  06500098
  Universities and colleges -- Jordan -- Administration; Jāmiʻah al-Urdunīyah
- Manpower resources in economic development: a background paper (Reports 000790), 1961; Hilliard, John F. (Box 40, Reel R-9301)
  The report reviews manpower resources as the most important factor in economic development.
  05900472
  Human capital; Occupational training; Personnel management; Economic development
- Observation regarding the establishment of a junior college of business administration at Beit Hanina (Reports 000791), 1965; Gilliam, John C. (Box 40)
  06200285
  The Regents Of The University Of Wisconsin
  Junior colleges -- Jordan; Industrial management -- Study and teaching -- Jordan; Teachers -- Training of -- Jordan; Business teachers -- Jordan
- Pilot inquire into organization and financing of the construction of Aswan 1964-1965? (Reports 000792), Glowczewski, Jerry; Zielinski, Z. A. (Zenon Albert) (Box 40)
  Housing and physical planning of Aswan, Arab Republic of Egypt are discussed.
  06390389
  Urbanization -- Egypt -- Aswan; City planning -- Egypt -- Aswan; Housing -- Egypt -- Aswan
- New government machinery for the coming phase (Reports 000793), 1966; Gulick, Luther Halsey, 1892-1993 (Box 40)
  Temporary new machinery is needed in the office of the prime minister of the Arab Republic of Egypt to restructure government methods and machinery for directive controlling and energizing the public-sector enterprise.
  06490463
  Political science -- Egypt
- Report on the Magdalena de Leal policy-related consultancy with CIERA (Center for Research and Studies of the Agrarian Reform) (Reports 000794), 1980; Flora, Cornelia Butler, 1943- (Box 40)
  Memo about Magdalena de Leal's consultancy on research on women in Nicaragua.
  Women in agriculture -- Nicaragua; Center for Research and Studies of the Agrarian Reform
- Educational planning and demonstrations in upgrading secondary education (Reports 000795), 1962; Figueroa, John J.; Doudna, Quincy (Box 40)
  The report is an evaluation of Antiguan secondary education and a recommendation for Ford Foundation support.
  06200511
  Educational planning -- Antigua; Education, Secondary -- Antigua; High schools -- Antigua; High school teachers -- Antigua
- A suggested philosophy of professional education for business and public administration and an illustrative curriculum working paper no. I (Reports 000796), 1965; Kozelka, Richard L. (Richard Louis), 1899- (Box 40)
  This report contains working papers no's. 1-6 of various titles. Title sufficient as abstract.
  Industrial management -- Study and teaching -- Jordan; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Jordan; Professional education -- Jordan; University Of Jordan
- Training course on management of science and technology in developing countries (Reports 000797), 1964; Arthur D. Little, Inc. (Box 40)
  The major topic under discussion was decentralization of technical activities versus centralization under a national planning and coordinating body.
  06190119
  Executives -- Training of -- Egypt; Technology -- Egypt; Arthur D. Little, Inc.
- Report to the rector of the University of Alexandria regarding chemical engineering education in Alexandria (Reports 000798), 1966; Maloney, James O. (Box 40)
  The purpose of the study was to make suggestions regarding the improvement of chemical engineering at the university so that graduates from the department of chemical engineering would be more able to assist in the development of the chemical industry in
  Chemical engineering -- Egypt; Engineering -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Egypt; Jāmiʻat al-Iskandarīyah
- Executive Conference Program: Visit to United Arab Republic by Dr. Albert A. Mavrinac and Morton J. Tenzer (Reports 000799), 1965; Mavrinac, Albert A.; Tenzer, Morton J., 1931- (Box 40, Reel R-9301)
  Executives -- Training of -- Egypt; Public administration -- Egypt; Executive Conference Program (Egypt)
- The hotel school of Lebanon (Reports 000800), 1965; Meek, Howard Bagnall (Box 40)
  The school is assessed in terms of its finances, facilities, staff, and programs.
  Vocational education -- Lebanon; Hotel School of Lebanon
- Puerto Rico's Joint Education Improvement Project (Reports 000804), 1966; Bohrson, Ralph G. (Box 40)
  Puerto Rico's curriculum development centers to improve course offerings in elementary and secondary schools are evaluated.
  06500147
  Curriculum planning -- Puerto Rico; Education, Elementary -- Puerto Rico; Education, Secondary -- Puerto Rico
- A report on a consultation with Dividendo Voluntario para la Comunidad of Venezuela (Reports 000816), 1965; Ciampa, Vincent F. (Box 40, Reel R-9301)
  The weaknesses, strengths and potential of Dividendo Voluntario para la Comunidad of Venezuela (DVC) are surveyed.
  Overseas Division/Latin America;Overseas Division/Latin America
  Social planning -- Venezuela; Dividendo Voluntario para la Comunidad (Organization)
- Report on trip to Venezuela (Reports 000819), 1963; Stolnitz, George J. (Box 40, Reel R-9301)
  An improvement program for the School of Economics at the Catholic University Andres Bello is discussed.
  Economics -- Study and teaching -- Venezuela; Catholic University Andres Bello (Caracas)
- Trip to Cali, December 4-13, 1963 (Reports 000820), 1964; O'Connor, Roderick F. (Box 40)
  A joint Universidad del Valle-Georgia Tech proposal for the establishment of a Graduate School in Industrial Management at the Universidad del Valle is discussed.
  Business education -- Venezuela; Industrial management -- Study and teaching -- Venezuela; Universidad del Valle; Georgia Institute of Technology
- Business participation in urban affairs (Reports 000821), 1965; Miller, S. M. (Seymour Michael), 1922- (Box 40)
  The business community's responsibilities in the decision making processes of the urban community is discussed.
  Cities and towns -- Research -- United States; Free enterprise -- United States; Civil rights -- United States; Social responsibility of business -- United States
- Agriculture program: Mexico (Reports 000822), 1964; Nagel, John S. (Box 40, Reel R-9301)
  The program in agriculture of the Ford Foundation is outlined.
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Mexico; Rural extension -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Research -- Mexico
- Personnel for overseas development (Reports 000824), 1962; Larson, Roy Edward (Box 40)
  Employment problems of aid-giving agencies, the availability of personnel from government, business and universities for overseas assignments and the role the Ford Foundation plays in helping to increase the supply and to improve the quality of such perso
  06290449
  Employment in foreign countries; International agencies -- Personnel management; Intercultural communication -- Foreign countries
- Personnel for overseas development: scope and methods of the study (Reports 000825), 1962; Larson, Roy Edward (Box 40)
  Methods selected that would make possible a reasonably thorough survey of the problems and possible solutions with reference to the quality of American overseas representation are discussed.
  Occupational surveys; Overseas employees; Employment in foreign countries; Professional employees; Civil service; United States. Agency for International Development
- Personnel for international development (Reports 000826), 1962; Thurber, Clarence E. (Box 40)
  The need for an appropriate contemporary analogue to a colonial service which would regularize overseas service on some kind of a career basis is discussed.
  Employment in foreign countries; Overseas employees; Professional employees; Civil service; United States. Agency for International Development
- Non-career specialists for overseas development (Reports 000827), 1962; Mosher, Frederick C. (Box 40)
  Professional employees -- Developing countries; Employment in foreign countries -- Developing countries; Overseas employees -- Developing countries; Civil service -- Developing countries; United States. Agency for International Development
- Use of public officials and employees in overseas development work with special emphasis on state and local personnel (Reports 000828), 1962; Pincus, William (Box 40)
  The need for restructuring domestic institutions and career lines to permit and to encourage foreign service as more of a normal part of a man's life career is discussed.
  Civil service -- Developing countries; Employment in foreign countries -- Developing countries; Overseas employees -- Developing countries; Professional employees -- Developing countries; United States. Agency for International Development
- Increasing the effectiveness of United States personnel overseas (Reports 000829), 1962; Steiglitz, Harold. (Box 40)
  The paper is a discussion of the need for a new breed of managers in American business who have sufficient scope and breadth to operate in a multinational and multicultural world.
  Overseas employees -- Training of; Overseas employees; Employment in foreign countries; Professional employees; Cross-cultural orientation
- Another look at university technical assistance projects abroad (Reports 000830), 1962; Weidner, Edward W. (Box 40)
  Universities and their relation to overseas contacting is discussed.
  Employment in foreign countries; Overseas employees; Universities and colleges; College teachers
- Development administration and law: an agenda for action by American universities (Reports 000831), 1962; Weidner, Edward W. (Box 40)
  Ways and means of improving the resource base in the United States for technical assistance overseas in development administration and law are discussed.
  Overseas employees -- Developing countries; Employment in foreign countries -- Developing countries; Universities and colleges -- Developing countries; Executives -- Training of -- Developing countries; Law -- Developing countries
- The United States economist and his participation in overseas assignments (Reports 000832), 1962; Dye, Richard W. (Box 40)
  How the resource base for technical assistance abroad in planning and economics can be improved by the joint effort of government, universities, international organizations, and private aid agencies is discussed.
  Overseas employees -- Developing countries; Employment in foreign countries -- Developing countries; Professional employees -- Developing countries
- Personnel for the new diplomacy: report of the Committee on Foreign Affairs Personnel, December 1962. (Reports 000833) (Box 40)
  The report urges drafting of legislation for submission to the congress in 1963 authorizing 1) creation of the post of Executive Under Secretary of State 2) establishment of a national foreign affairs college 3) institution of basic changes in the foreign
  Professional employees; Overseas employees; Employment in foreign countries; International relations
- Problems of personnel for overseas service in West Europe (Reports 000834), 1962; Heaps, David (Box 40)
  Employment in foreign countries -- France; Employment in foreign countries -- England; Overseas employees -- France; Professional employees -- England
- What the Ford Foundation has done to improve the sources and increase the availability of overseas personnel (Reports 000835), 1962; Saunders, Irwin T. (Box 40)
  Employment in foreign countries; Overseas employees; Overseas employees -- Training of; Professional employees; Subsidies
- Three economic papers on agriculture in Syria (Reports 000836), 1966; Korzan, Gerald E. (Gerald Earl); Jāmiʻat Ḥalab (Box 41, Reel R-9301)
  Foods demands, the importance of international agricultural trade, and cotton yields are discussed.
  06400298;06490418
  University Of Aleppo
  Agricultural research publication;no. 2